Contact

wisemandv@aol.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ davidandrewwiseman (LinkedIn) davidandrewwiseman.brandyourself.c (Personal)

Top Skills

CMMI

Software Development Process Improvement

Publications

SOTIF – a missed input to the 26262 HARA

David Andrew Wiseman

David Andrew Wiseman is the Global Functional Safety Manager at IEE

Summary

David Andrew Wiseman is an expert in Functional Safety
Management to ISO 26262. This includes, how to foster a positive
safety culture, role specific training, safety planning and monitoring.
Also the performance of the complete concept phase (ADAS level
2, 2.5 and 3), system, software and hardware development. In
addition, technical safety concept, safety analysis, confirmation
reviews, safety audit and safety assessment.

Project Management for Software Development, Software Methods and Tools Consultancy and Process Maturity Assessment and Certification.

Specialties: Software Development, Process Improvement, ISO 15504 (SPICE), CMMI, Automotive SPICE, IEC 61508 and ISO 26262 Safety Standards

Experience

ISO - International Organization for Standardization Working Group Member April 2017 - Present

TC22/SC32/WG8 Functional Safety ISO 26262

ISO - International Organization for Standardization Working Group Member April 2017 - Present

TC22/SC32/WG11 Automotive Cybersecurity ISO 21434

IEE

Global Functional Safety Manager October 2012 - Present

Luxembourg

IEE

Process Improvement and Process Quality Assurance Manager December 2008 - Present

IEE

3 years 9 months

Software Development Manager November 2007 - July 2010 (2 years 9 months)

Luxembourg

Managing all aspects of embedded software development for automotive products.

Software Quality Assurance November 2006 - November 2007 (1 year 1 month)

Responsible for project managing the roll out of Automotive SPICE.

Visteon

7 years

Process Improvement Manager
May 2005 - October 2006 (1 year 6 months)

Product Validation Manager May 2004 - May 2005 (1 year 1 month)

Systems \ Software Development Manager November 1999 - May 2004 (4 years 7 months)

Powertrain Control Systems and then Audio Systems

Ford Motor Company
Software Lead / Architect
November 1992 - November 1999 (7 years 1 month)

Software engineer for powertrain control systems, 4 years in the UK and 3 years in Detroit.

GEC Marconi

Software Engineer

September 1986 - October 1992 (6 years 2 months)

Electro-Optics Division, working on airborne systems.

Education

Brunel University London
BSc (Hons.), Applied Physics · (1986 - 1990)

Brunel University London

Bachelor of Science - BS, Engineering Physics/Applied Physics